<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joshua R Lowry</title>
    <description>Developer turned designer. 
</description>
    <link>http://joshualowry.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://joshualowry.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 04:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 04:07:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minimistish</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have always had a problem keeping things, and really that is getting rid of things. I am finding that this inability to dispose of things alters the way I feel about my life. When we got engaged we started looking really hard at our finances. Before I begin, we didn’t have any major debt beyond one car loan. Most of our “financial issues” were related to not having a solid plan, and thus excess posessions and a little lifestyle inflation have prevailed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to give the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.daveramsey.com/store/financial-peace-university/financial-peace-university-home-study-kit/prod163.html?ictid=ZN67X366&quot;&gt;Dave Ramsey’s Financial Peace University&lt;/a&gt; a whirl. With the tools, we built out our budget of things we pay for, and had some serious discussions about how much money we want to save. With that information, we started cutting out some of the things that we deemed “low value”. We transferred all of our regular payments to one credit card (paid off monthly) and went to a cash budget for food and fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started by filtering new purchases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If we buy this, where will we put it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we started examining existing items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Realistically, when is the next time we will use this, and is there an alternative?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got rid of clothes, video games, and trinkets by selling, donating, or trashing. We stopped going to stores without a specific goal in mind, and we began only purchasing clothes that fit perfectly and felt good. We started to have a PLAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t long before we realized how much time and money was spent cleaning and organizing &lt;em&gt;things&lt;/em&gt;. This was compounded when we had to rush to make our apartment look tidy for guests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With our new found time and money, we decided to invest in our fitness. We joined the local gym and started meeting with a personal trainer to help us understand how to build a workout that works for our goals. While on this adventure, we discovered the health benefits of cooking more. It was the fitness that helped us get started with cooking, and our pocket book realized the benefits almost immediately. The savings on food completely paid for our gym membership and the trainer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly thereafter, my wife read some of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mrmoneymustache.com/&quot;&gt;Mr. Money Mustache’s&lt;/a&gt; blog, and we started to realize how living more simply can really reduce a lot of stress and free up funds for saving. MMM helped us to focus on financial independence, that we don’t &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to work. His post on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mrmoneymustache.com/2012/01/13/the-shockingly-simple-math-behind-early-retirement/&quot;&gt;Shockingly Simple Math Behind Early Retirement&lt;/a&gt; tells us that if we save 15% we will need to work 43 years, but if we can save 50% we will only need to work 17. As we have worked hard to achieve this level of financial freedom, we have gained more confidence at work to achieve the career goals we really want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;169&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GgBpyNsS-jU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;float: left; padding-right:10px&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I saw the TED Talk [left] for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theminimalists.com/&quot;&gt;The Minimalists&lt;/a&gt;. Their methods seem quite aggressive, but they do have me thinking about the &lt;em&gt;things&lt;/em&gt; and what their purpose is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our winter break we finally “unpacked” the remaining boxes that have been waiting for us for over a year. We found so many things that we forgot we had. We donated or trashed nearly half of it. I remember some things, old movies that are freely available through our content subscriptions, some books not worth re-reading, clothes that don’t fit, and a ton of things that aren’t even other people’s treasures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Stop buying the unnecessary.&lt;br /&gt;
Toss half your stuff, learn contentedness.&lt;br /&gt;
Reduce half again.&lt;br /&gt;
List 4 essential things in your life, do these first,&lt;br /&gt;
stop doing the non-essential.&lt;br /&gt;
Clear distractions, focus on each moment.&lt;br /&gt;
Let go of attachment to doing, having more.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Fall in love with less.&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;http://mnmlist.com/less/&quot;&gt;mnmlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TV Free January has already been more productive. Perhaps I will be able to release some more posessions and free myself from some additional burdens.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://joshualowry.com/transformation/finance/2016/01/12/Minimistish.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joshualowry.com/transformation/finance/2016/01/12/Minimistish.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>transformation</category>
        
        <category>finance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have now been on vacation for two solid weeks, and it is approximately three hours till 2016. With Champaigne (cough &lt;em&gt;Sparkling Wine&lt;/em&gt;) in hand, I write this post. We will continue with our tradition of TV Free January (Netflix, HULU, and Prime), where we vow to do better things with our time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to accomplish these “better things” my wife and I sat down and authored a document to help us realize our long term goals. We made a 20 year outlook for our finances and made plans for how we would save this year to stay on track. We decided on vacations (and budgets), plans for home improvement and major purchases, and narrowed down our monthly budget to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getrichslowly.org/blog/2009/10/19/pay-yourself-first/&quot;&gt;pay ourselves first&lt;/a&gt;! We also created a handy &lt;a href=&quot;/tools/groceries/&quot;&gt;Static Grocery List&lt;/a&gt; which we will use to help us keep our grocery purchases in check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After gaining a better understanding of our financial goals we moved into our personal goals for the year. You will see that a large component of my goals relate to fitness, socialization, and education. In 2016 I want to stop being a &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/99498062&quot;&gt;Couchlandrian&lt;/a&gt;! Here are some of mine. We tried to use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SMART_criteria&quot;&gt;S.M.A.R.T Template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;goal-increase-my-physical-fitness-and-lose-weight&quot;&gt;Goal: Increase my physical fitness and lose weight.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specific:&lt;/strong&gt; Perform 45 minutes a day of physical exercise of at least a walk 5 days a week and participate in Cycling Training Rides (1 per week). Consult with Health Coach and Personal Trainer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measurable:&lt;/strong&gt; 180 pounds by 2017 (currently 200 pounds) and Daily 45 Minute Goal with a cycling training ride.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attainable:&lt;/strong&gt; I used to do this, and I want to do it again.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant:&lt;/strong&gt; I am heavily invested in cycling, and I find it relaxing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time-Bound:&lt;/strong&gt; Measured Weekly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;goal-increase-participation-in-cycling-community&quot;&gt;Goal: Increase participation in cycling community.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specific:&lt;/strong&gt; Maintain Energy Riders Training Series Website&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measurable:&lt;/strong&gt; 2 Hours Minimum Per Week&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attainable:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, assuming TV is not available&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant:&lt;/strong&gt; Participating in the Energy Riders Training Series is one of my primary hobbies, and cycling is a focal point for my fitness goals.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time-Bound:&lt;/strong&gt; Series ends in April.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;goal-learn-more-about-user-experience-design&quot;&gt;Goal: Learn more about User Experience Design&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specific:&lt;/strong&gt; Watch two &lt;a href=&quot;http://aycl.uie.com/&quot;&gt;All You Can Learn&lt;/a&gt; talks per week.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measurable:&lt;/strong&gt; Two per week sounds pretty easy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attainable:&lt;/strong&gt; My company pays for them, and I will watch them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant:&lt;/strong&gt; These videos will help me learn more skills for my work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time-Bound:&lt;/strong&gt; Currently there are 242 seminars, I will be on track to watch 104 of them in one year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;goal-work-on-fun-coding-projects-with-others&quot;&gt;Goal: Work on fun coding projects with others.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specific:&lt;/strong&gt; For 5 hours per week, work on coding projects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measurable:&lt;/strong&gt; 5 hours is pretty lean.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attainable:&lt;/strong&gt; TV holds me back on this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant:&lt;/strong&gt; Coding projects are constrained only by our imagination (and of course our time….), note: bring imagination.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time-Bound:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;goal-entertain-guests-at-our-house&quot;&gt;Goal: Entertain guests at our house.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specific:&lt;/strong&gt; Host an event with 2-10 guests once per month and make simple snacks like mini cupcakes or popcorn to keep it light.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measurable:&lt;/strong&gt; As simple as a small game night to a large movie night.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attainable:&lt;/strong&gt; We could probably do it more!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant:&lt;/strong&gt; Entertaining is fun, it can be healthy, and even with snacks is pretty cheap.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time-Bound:&lt;/strong&gt; Once per month for this year, or more if we can manage it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;goal-one-chore-per-day&quot;&gt;Goal: One Chore Per Day&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specific:&lt;/strong&gt; Pick one chore per day from the household chore list. If it leads to more than one, that is a win!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measurable:&lt;/strong&gt; Just ONE!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attainable:&lt;/strong&gt; Most chores take 20 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant:&lt;/strong&gt; Keeping the house tidy and clean reduces our stress and allows us to feel productive and focus on our other goals.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time-Bound:&lt;/strong&gt; ONE PER DAY!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;goal-tabletop-gaming-day&quot;&gt;Goal: Tabletop Gaming Day&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specific:&lt;/strong&gt; Play the &lt;a href=&quot;http://paizo.com/pathfinder/adventurePath/riseOfTheRunelords&quot;&gt;Rise of the Runelords Campaign&lt;/a&gt; once per month at least.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measurable:&lt;/strong&gt; Gaming days take a whole day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attainable:&lt;/strong&gt; Prep work has been reduced down to an hour or two with the help of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wolflair.com/legacy/index.php?context=hero_lab&amp;amp;page=pathfinder_roleplaying_game&quot;&gt;HeroLab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant:&lt;/strong&gt; Rise of the Runelords is fun and challenging for me to host.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time-Bound:&lt;/strong&gt; Eventually the campaign will be over, and I will have to find new campaigns to play.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is that chore list? The chore list is our system for communicating the things we need to get done on a daily or weekly basis.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Daily&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
* Dishes&lt;br /&gt;
* Tidying the Kitchen or Public Areas&lt;br /&gt;
* Laundry&lt;br /&gt;
* Mail&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Weekly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
* Poop Scoop&lt;br /&gt;
* Lawncare&lt;br /&gt;
* Mop Floors&lt;br /&gt;
* Bathroom Wipedown&lt;br /&gt;
* Dusting&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Stepouts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
* Catalog Books&lt;br /&gt;
* Dusting&lt;br /&gt;
* Washing Couch Cushions&lt;br /&gt;
* Washing Bedding&lt;br /&gt;
* Organizing Garage&lt;br /&gt;
* Cleaning Cars&lt;br /&gt;
* Weeding&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://joshualowry.com/design/strategy/2015/12/31/NewYear.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joshualowry.com/design/strategy/2015/12/31/NewYear.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Beginnings: Develop Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since before I got my first computer, my family knew that I would choose a career in computing. It wasn’t until I decided on a degree in Computer Science that they realized how deep that would go. Since 2009, I have been designing/developing/testing software for my  job. A few years ago I was talking with one of my mentors and pondering why it was that we didn’t have a center of experts within the group who focus on Human Computer Interaction or even bigger, User Experience Design. The opportunity to break through into the UX space has finally arrived for us, and I will soon be embarking on a journey from Developer to Designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had the opportunity to go to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://uxpa2015.org/&quot;&gt;User Experience Professionals 2015 Conference&lt;/a&gt; in San Diego/Coronoado Bay, California. It was there that I discovered that there is an amazing group of people doing things that I had only dreamed of. Many companies have gone through the same transformation, but by different means leaving me with a wealth of knowledge to build upon. Seeing their success makes me hopeful that we can grow our user-centered focus and ultimately bring delight to our users.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://joshualowry.com/transformation/2015/08/25/NewBeginnings.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joshualowry.com/transformation/2015/08/25/NewBeginnings.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>transformation</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
